let quiz=[
    {
      question: "Which among the following is not a correct pair :",
      option: [
           "Ellora Caves-Rastrakuta Rulers",
           "Mahabalipuram-Pallava Rulers",
           "Khajuraho-Chandellas",
           "Elephanta Caves-Maurya Era",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which among the following Kavya of Sanskrit, deal with court intrigues & access to power of Chandragupta Maurya :",
      option: [
           "Mrichhakatika",
           "Ritusamhara",
           "Kumarasambhava",
           "Mudrarakshahsa",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "On which of the following systems of Hindu Philosophy, Shankaracharya wrote commentary in 9th century AD :",
      option: [
           "Sankhya",
           "Vaisheshika",
           "Yoga",
           "Uttarmimansa",
      ],
       answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "The eighth-century tripartite power struggle was among which of the following :",
      option: [
           "Cholas, Rastrakutas and Yadavas",
           "Chalukyas, Pallavas and Pandyas",
           "Cholas, Pandyas and Chalukyas",
           "Chalukyas, Pallavas and Yadavas",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Which among the following is not correct :",
      option: [
           "The capital of pandyas was Madurai",
           "The capital of Cheras was Vanchi",
           "Capital of the Videha Kingdom-Mithila",
           "Capital of Gahadwal Dynasty-Kannauj",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Which king started the organization of Kumbh fair at Allahabad :",
      option: [
           "Harshavardhana",
           "Dhruvasena li",
           "Narshimhvarman",
           "Akabar",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Upnishads are books on :",
      option: [
           "Politics",
           "Philosophy",
           "Medicine",
           "Social life",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Who was the first Indian ruler who had territory outside India :",
      option: [
           "Ashoka",
           "Chandragupta Maurya",
           "Kanishka",
           "Huvishka",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following statement is wrong :",
      option: [
           "Sunga dynasty was founded by pushyamitra",
           "Ashoka the great Mauryan king died in 332 BC",
           "Ashoka invaded the kalinga in 261 BC",
           "Chandragupta Maurya earned the title of the Liberator",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Who among the following was worshipped during Early Vedic Civilisation :",
      option: [
           "Varuna",
           "Indra",
           "Surya",
           "All of the above",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
  question: "Which among the following is the oldest Dynasty ?",
  option: [
  "Maurya",
  "Gupta",
  "kushan",
  "Kanva",
  ],
  answer: 1, 
},
{
  question: "Aryabhatta believed to have been born in 5th century AD,was a most renowned scholar of :",
  option: [
  "Astronomy",
  "Biology",
  "Medicine",
  "Physiology",
  ],
  answer: 1, 
},
{
  question: "The most famous Chera Ruler was",
  option: [
  "Udiyanjeral",
  "Nedunjeraladan",
  "Sengutuvan",
  "Sengannan",
  ],
  answer: 3, 
},
{
  question: "Which of the following leader was not present in the very first meeting of Indian National Congress ?",
  option: [
  "Dadabhai Naroji",
  "Kashinath Trimbak Telang",
  "Pherozeshah Mehta",
  "Surendranth Banerjee",
  ],
  answer: 4, 
},
{
  question: "Who told Indian Congree represents only Microscopic Minorities ?",
  option: [
  "Lord Curzon",
  "Lord Dufferin",
  "Lord Minto",
  "None of These",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},
    ]    
